

Sameer Kamran

Date of birth: 26/11/1995 | **Nationality:** Pakistani | **Gender** Male | (+49) 1774052203 |

me@sameerkamran.com | sameerkamran.com |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sameer-kamran-dev/

Koblenzer Str. 236, 56073, Koblenz, Germany

About me: Sameer is an Intermediate level Software Engineer, who is graduated in 2017 with the degree in Information Technology. He has experience of around 3 years in software industry in Pakistan, specifically in Web Development technologies. Recently relocated to Koblenz, Germany. Looking for opportunities to showcase my skills and to learn more in my field.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/06/2019 – 13/10/2020 – Lahore, Pakistan

DOT NET / ANGULAR DEVELOPER - BOLTECH SOLUTIONS

My responsibilities here, were to design databases, software architecture, and direct communication with clients.

- Worked on Tax Management System for Government of Malawi, Africa (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, AutoMapper, Autofac, Angular 6, Angular Material, PrimeNg)
- Worked on GYM Management System for UFC Gym International (.Net Core 3.0, MySQL, SignalR, AutoMapper, Audofac, Angular 8, Angular Material, ZKTeco Access Gates Integration)
- Worked on Employee Service Catalogue & Digital Approvals System for Exceed IT Services (ExpressJS, Mongoose, MongoDB, Angular 7)

Lahore, Pakistan

01/03/2018 – 01/06/2019 – Lahore, Pakistan **SOFTWARE ENGINEER –** CODILITY SOLUTIONS

Developed multiple Software/Solutions for clients around the world, was part of the requirement gathering team as well.

- Worked on Purchase Order Management Web Application (.Net Core 2.1 WebApi, SQL Server, .Net MVC5, KnockoutJS, VanillaJS, SQL Server)
- Worked on Inventory/Point-of-Sale Desktop Application (WPF, SQLite, MvvmCross, DevExpress)
- Worked on Office Management System. Attendance/Task Management (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, ZKTeco Biometric Integration)

Lahore, Pakistan

01/02/2019 - 02/06/2019 - Lahore, Pakistan

REMOTE SOFTWARE ENGINEER - HIGHBIT TECHNOLOGIES LTD.

Worked on a short-term POS Application built using .Net Core, Angular and one of the system was on Laravel.

01/04/2017 - 15/07/2017 - Lahore, Pakistan

.NET DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP) - INSEPARABLE TECHNOLOGY PVT. LTD.

Did my internship for around 3 months, Learnt a lot about how development cycle actually works.

• Worked on an Ecommerce Store (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, OAuth, Social Media Integration)

Lahore, Pakistan

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

07/10/2013 - 12/12/2017 - Lahore, Pakistan

BS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - University of the Punjab

Basic Programming, Data Structure and Algorithms, Networking e.t.c

Asp .Net MVC5,C#,Bootstrap,JQuery

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

Server Side:.Net Core. Asp .Net MVC5, EF/EFCore, SignalR, Autofac, ExpressJS, Mongoose, Laravel

Client Side: Angular 2+, NgRx, Angular Material, PrimeNG, GraphQL Apolo, ReactJS, Materila UI, Bootstrap, JQuery,

KnockoutIS

Database: MS SQL Server, SQL Server Compact, MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud: AWS(EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, S3, Route53)

Others: GIT, SVN

DIGITAL SKILLS

Management tools (JIRA, Confluence) | Microsoft Office | Collaboration (Teams, Slack, Zoom, Webex, Miro u.a.) | Asana

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): URDU

Other language(s):

	UNDERST	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING	
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C1	C1	C1	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user